peaceful peaceful in 2016 than it was in
2015 and there are now fewer countries
in the world which can be truly
considered at peace in other words not
engaged in any conflicts either what
internally or externally then there were
in 2014 so needless to say our world is
engaged in warfare in many many
different places and you just wonder our
things gonna get better or will they
continue to get worse
how about terrorism I mean before 2011
terrorism was something that we rarely
talked about after 2000 I'm sorry 2001
terrorism was something we rarely talked
about after that
it kind of changed the face of
everything we now live in a world where
terrorism can happen at any time in any
place our world appears to be in serious
danger how about this polarization just
take a look at the screen I don't even
have to say anything you can look at
that screen and I can probably guess
that emotions even now may be rolling up
inside some people here right think
about what our nation is going through
think about the the hatred the anger
think about all these things and this
leads us to the question what in the
world is going on like one study shows
that America Americans are more divided
along party lines than ever
one study actually said since the Civil
War so here's the deal we want answers
we want to know young people want to
know older people will know everyone
across this planet
really wants to know what in the world
is going on and and when you're looking
for answers you really have to decide
one thing where am I going to get my
answers from so if I were to say to you
hey guys you know where I get my answers
from I get my answers from Fox News how
many of you would roll your eyes and
then if I said no I'm just kidding I get
my answers from MSNBC the other half
would probably roll their eyes here's a
question are these reliable sources Fox
News MSNBC CNN ABC Breitbart Alex Jones
the Internet
all right many of us get our sore our
newsroom from there and and you know
what let me say to a certain degree all
these all these sources are doing are
they are they're giving us the news from
their perspective
but what we want to know is is there
Aaron who died of a source that can tell
us without a shadow of a doubt what is
actually going on and I believe the
answer is yes I'm going to show you
where I get my news from so I get my
news from I'm trying to think of a well
anyway I get my news from the Bible bi b
l e not a b c NB c bi b and e and let me
tell you why i want you to notice these
words in matthew 24 verse 6 Jesus
speaking here just about 2000 years ago
said these words and you shall hear of
wars and rumors of wars are we hearing
of wars and rumors of wars right now you
know our people kind of worried about
what's gonna happen with North Korea
yeah they're a little bit of like hey
what's going on like you know who would
have thought we'd be talking about this
at this time in Earth's history so so so
the Bible said thousands of years before
that there would be wars and rumors of
wars and then it says see that you be
not troubled now does that make sense
you see that you do you know their
rewards and rumors of wars but see that
you be not troubled that to me sounds
very strange if there are wars and
rumors of wars like I'm going to be
troubled but the Bible is actually
telling us listen I'm letting you know
ahead of time what's coming and I'm
telling you that when you see these
things don't be troubled because
something else is going on there's a
bigger picture I want you to grasp and I
want to share with you
ilan they're asking the question what in
the world is going on but they don't see
the bigger picture and that's why we're
here tonight we want to know what is
that bigger picture so let's read on it
says you shall hear of wars and rumors
of wars see that you be not troubled for
all these things must come to pass but
the end is not yet Matthew 24:7 for
nation shall rise against nation and
Kingdom against Kingdom and there shall
be famines and pestilences and
earthquakes in diverse places is this
true
like even if you didn't believe in the
Bible let's say oh you know I don't
believe the Bible it's a book of
fairytales but someone dragged me here
tonight so I decided to come even if
that was the case don't anyone look at
me like how did you know just I'm just
saying even if that was the case would
you say that this verse this you know
forget about written or this verse is it
a true statement
can you look and at what's going on
today and say you know what I may not
believe in the Bible but that right
there is true yeah I would say
absolutely this is absolutely true so
there shall be famines and pestilences
and earthquakes in diverse places and
then it says all these are the
beginnings of Sorrows it's not the end
of Sorrows it's the beginning of sores
in other words other things are to come
now that would really make someone
nervous well if these are just the
beginnings of troubles like what else is
to come and yet we're told do not be
troubled
do not fear listen why trust the Bible
for answers why should we trust the
Bible over Fox News MSNBC see it why
should we trust the Bible not putting
any of these other sources of news down
but why trust the Bible when we want to
get the picture of what's going on well
let me tell you why
I'm gonna tell you why I trust the Bible
so take a good look if you see a young
man with red dreadlocks there I am right
there that's me almost 20 years ago now
more than 20 years ago and that's me as
a hip-hop artist that is me as a secular
person who did not believe in the Bible
and then something happened to me in my
experience that led me to see the Bible
as a divinely inspired book growing up
as a skeptic of religion I always kind
of felt like you know people were just
religious because of the place in which
they were brought up in so you know if
you were born in you know a country that
was predominantly Muslim then naturally
you'd be Muslim because that's the
country you were born in or Buddhist or
any scientist well people in America who
are Christians are really just
Christians because that's the
predominant religion in America and I
thought to myself that's not a good
reason to be any kind of religion so
therefore I think this whole thing all
religions are really just shams they're
made up their fairy tales they're
they're just they're untruthful and then
I had an experience that I cannot get
into the details of it now because that
would be a whole different subject in
and of itself but let me just say this
I'm gonna take you to a verse that
changed everything for me
because I did not know this but God
Himself put a chair
in the bible to basically validate that
he is who he says he is and that there
is no other God upon the planet in other
words he puts out a challenge and when I
saw this challenge it changed everything
for me
so let me read to you that challenge
it's found in Isaiah chapter 41 verse 22
here's what it says
let them this is God speaking let them
speaking about the other gods so what
God do you worship do you worship Allah
do you worship you no are you Buddhist
or whatever whatever God it is you
worship he says let them bring them
forth and show us what shall happen what
shall happen in other words God is here
saying listen if your God can tell you
the future then let him be God if he
can't tell you the future he is not God
let me read it again let them bring
forth and show us what shall happen let
them show the former things what they be
that we may consider them and know the
latter end of them or declare us things
for to come so the things that are to
come here after that you that we may
know that you are gods
yay do good or evil that we may be
dismayed and behold it God is giving out
a challenge here to all the people who
are worshipping other gods thing listen
bring your gods together and if your God
can tell you the future then he's gone
now thought to myself that is a pretty
serious challenge because I know that
there is no scientific explanation for
being able to foretell the future
hundreds or thousands of years in a
there is no science for that people are
always trying to forecast and and the
most they can forecast is you know by
you know the weather you know this is
what the weather will be in this and
sometimes they get it wrong and this
just based on science okay I'm gonna
forecast based on science God forecasts
based on his own power so he is Bey
we're saying bring all your holy books
together bring all your gods together
and search these holy books to see if
they accurately foretell the future and
if they do not accurately foretell the
future than they are fought there are
non-existent gods
when I saw that challenge you know what
I did
I started going to all these different
religions and seeing do they have
prophecy you know things that foretell
the future not very broad and you know
broad things like the world will get
worse to me that was a very you know I
mean okay yeah we could we don't need
prophecy to tell us that we can see the
world being a bad place we can see the
world possibly getting worse so to me
that was a very broad thing no I wanted
something very specific and guess what
the Bible had it the Bible had it listen
Isaiah 42 verse 9 behold
the former things are come to pass and
new things do I declare before they
spring forth I tell you of them God
again is telling us that what sets him
aside from every other from every other
religion from every every other entity
that claims to be God is that he can
tell the future now how many of you
would just be like man if I could know
the future that would make me feel a
whole lot better because when you know
the future the uncertainty is gone right
you're not like I wonder you know it's
just all going to be destroyed by a
nuclear bomb like you know you just have
all these thoughts what's gonna happen
but if someone were able to tell you hey
listen don't worry about it we're not
going to war with this nation this or
this or this will not happen you want to
have a greater peace because you knew
the future and God is saying listen Fox
News can't tell you the future MSNBC
can't tell you the future whatever holy
book you're reading cannot tell you the
future there is only one God and one
book that has the future as its news and
that is in the Bible so one more isaiah
4 verse 6 thus saith the lord the king
of israel and his redeemer the lord of
hosts i am the first and the last beside
me there is no god and who as i shall
call and shall de
clear it and set it in order for me
since I appointed the ancient people are
the thing and the things that are coming
and shall come let them show unto us
this is just more of God giving out the
same challenge in the same book so with
that in mind I want to share with you
tonight just one just one such prophecy
that basically will answer the question
for us tonight what in the world is
going on that prophecy is found in the
Book of Daniel the Book of Daniel was
written around the 6th century BC so
when everyone let me just hear you
repeat the 6th century BC that's when
the Book of Daniel was written so let me
just say this way The Book of Daniel was
written a very very very very very very
very long time ago make sense so far all
right so we need to understand that
because what we are about to see in the
Book of Daniel is actually news about
what is going on right now even though
it was written thousands of years ago it
is news about what's going on right now
and God gives us this prophecy so that
he can show us listen if you want
someone to trust I would be that one why
because I am able to tell you the future
and if I demonstrate to you that I can
tell you the future then you can rest
assured that you can trust me when I say
this this and this is going to come to
pass by the way how many of you would
like your own personal I'm able to tell
you the future person I mean just
imagine how fun life would be hey should
I go on that road or should I go on that
road no you need to go on this I mean
huh well guess what man can't do that
but God God says I want you to trust me
with your future see God is not just
trying to impress us with you know hey I
can tell the future
isn't that cool no he's saying listen if
you are worried about your future there
is someone you can trust with that
future and that
me so let me give you prophecy to
demonstrate to you that I hold your
future in my hands and if you see that
then I'm inviting you to put your future
in my hands I'm inviting you to trust me
and what I say that's what God is trying
to do all right so here's here's a
prophecy that we see in the Book of
Daniel and by the way this is just one
prophecy in the Book of Daniel it's
found in Daniel chapter 2 in Daniel
chapter 2 our Daniel is a Hebrew prophet
that has been taken captive by a kingdom
named Babylon and so as Daniel is as
we're reading this account of Daniel
chapter 2 remember Daniel is a Hebrew
slave the nation of Israel had rebelled
against God and as a result of their
rebelling against God they ended up in
captivity to this nation called Babylon
and here Daniel we read about one of
Daniels first experiences in Babylon and
here it says in Daniel 2 verse 1 in the
second year of the reign of
Nebuchadnezzar that would be the king of
Babylon Nebuchadnezzar dreamed dreams
wherewith his spirit troubled him and
his sleep break from him so just to
recap very quickly
who's the king and what does he have
alright and the dream does what to him
it troubles him verse 2 then the king
commanded to call the magicians and the
astrologers and the sorceress and the
Chaldeans
for to show the king his dream so they
came instead before the king and the
king said unto them I have dreamed the
dream and my spirit was troubled to know
the dream then state the Chaldeans to
the king in Syriac Oh King live forever
tell thy servants the dream and we will
show the interpretation the King
answered and said to the Chaldeans the
thing is gone from me and if you will
not make known unto me the dream with
the interpretation thereof you shall be
cut in pieces and your houses shall be
made a dunghill all right so that's a
threat for those of you didn't catch
that
the king has a dream he cannot remember
the dream so he goes to his sorcerers
and his magicians and his Wiseman and
says to them
give me the dream I had a dream I
Cameron what it was tell me the dream
because they're supposed to be able to
know how to do this but guess what they
don't know what he dreamed and he says
to them oh you guys have basically been
fooling me if you don't give me the
interpretation of the dream I'm gonna
kill you so they're now worried and they
say they answered and said let the King
tell his servants to dream and we will
show the interpretation of it the King
answered and said I know of a certainty
that you would gain from me the time
gained the time because you see the
thing is gone from me but if you will
not make known unto me the dream there
is but one decree for you for you have
prepared a lying and corrupt words to
speak before me till the time be changed
therefore tell me the dream and I shall
know that you can that you can show me
the interpretation thereof they did not
have the power to know what he was
thinking in his mind you know why
because only God knows the thoughts and
the feelings and so uh the Bible says in
verse 12 they could not do this so in
verse 12 the king was angry and very
furious and commanded to destroy all the
wise men of Babylon and the decree went
forth that the wise men should be slain
and they saw Daniel and his fellows to
be slain now Daniel and his friends were
not invited to give the the king the
interpretation of the dream so when they
get this decree when they hear this
decree they're wondering what is this
decree about and so when Daniel finds
out the Bible says in verse 16 then
Daniel went in and desired of the King
that he would give him the time and that
he would show the king the
interpretation then Daniel went to his
house and made the thing known to
Hananiah Mishael and Azariah his
companions that they would desire the
mercies of the God of heaven concerning
this secret that Daniel and his fellows
should not perish with the rest of the
wise men of Babylon let me pause right
here so for some of you who have never
heard this before
you're probably finger right now pastor
what in the world
have to do with what in the world is
going on pause let me tell you it has
everything to do with what is going on
right now so I'm just saying stay
focused don't lose me don't zoom out
don't stay I'm gonna wait for the good
part no no no no this is the good part
all right so then verse 19 then was the
secret revealed on to Daniel in a night
vision then Daniel blessed the God of
heaven so according to the Bible God
gives Daniel the understanding of the
dream and its meaning all right you got
that so far yes okay so Daniel verse 27
Daniel answered in the presence of the
king and said the secret which the King
has demanded cannot the wise men the
astrologers and the magicians the
soothsayers show unto the king but there
is a God in heaven that revealeth
secrets and make if known to the king
Nebuchadnezzar what shall be in the
flask your question latter days what
does that mean to you latter days that
would be one the end of time okay so
Daniel the Book of Daniel was written in
the sixth century BC that's around 600
in the six hundredth century beyond 600
BC Daniel is given an understanding of
events that are to occur when in the
latter days in the latter days so now if
we want to know what in the world is
going on maybe a good place to start
would be the dream so here's what Daniel
says Daniel is about to give him the
dream and here's what he says the
visions of our head upon thy bed are
these as for thee O king thy thoughts
came into thy mind upon thy bed once
should come to pass Hereafter and he
that reveal his secrets
maketh known to thee what shall come to
pass now this is powerful to me because
Daniel doesn't does not only tell the
king
he's not just about to tell the King
what he dreamed he actually tells the
King what he was thinking before he
dozed off into sleep you guys catch that
he said you were thinking about what
should come to pass when Hereafter so
what was the King thinking what was this
king of Babylon what was going through
his mind hey what what does the future
hold have you ever thought about that
what does the future hold are we
thinking about that right now
hey what does the future hold for
America what does the future hold for
the world like what this is exactly what
Nebuchadnezzar was thinking when he
falls asleep and then he has this dream
so here's what we know so far we know
that whatever this dream is it has
number one to do with the latter days
and number two this is exactly what
Nebuchadnezzar was thinking hey what
will happen
what will happen here after so here is
the Dream Thou O king sauce and behold a
great image this great image whose
brightness was excellent stood before
thee and the form thereof was terrible
the images head was a fine gold his
breast and his arms of silver his belly
and his thighs of brass his legs of iron
his feet part of iron and part of clay
thou sawest till that a stone was cut
out without hands which smote the image
upon his feet that were of iron and clay
and break them to pieces then was the
iron the clay the brass the silver and
the gold broke into pieces together and
became like the chaff of the summer
threshing floors and the wind carried
them away that no place was found for
them and the stone that smote the image
became a great mountain and filled the
whole earth so here is a picture of what
Nebuchadnezzar dreamed he saw in his
dream an image can you guys repeat that
for me just very quickly he saw an image
remember that ok keep that word in mind
he saw an image it's an image of a man
the man had a head of gold chest and
arms of silver belly and thighs of brass
legs of iron and toes of iron and clay
and then a stone is cut out without
hands that hits the image where on its
feet and then the whole image shatters
to pieces and that stone grows into a
great mountain alright I know that
sounds like wait what in the world like
we did Nebuchadnezzar eat something
before he went to bed but that's not
what happened God is showing nothing
there's something so here's what happens
daniel to verse 36 daniel now says this
this is the dream and we will tell the
interpretation thereof before the king
thou o king are the king of kings for
the god of heaven has given via kingdom
power and strength and glory
wheresoever the children of men dwell
with the beasts of the field and the
fowls of the heaven has he given into
thine hand and has made thee ruler over
them all
thou art this head of gold so what is
Daniel telling Nebuchadnezzar right here
Nebuchadnezzar the dream you had of the
image of a man who had a golden head
he's saying Nebuchadnezzar you and your
kingdom
what was his kingdom Babylon this
represents you and your kingdom you are
that head of gold so far to ask you hey
guys in Daniels prophecy in Daniel
chapter 2 this image appears in
Nebuchadnezzar's dream and the head is
of gold you would say to me all pastor
it's simple that head of gold represents
the Babylonian Empire here's what he
says after and after thee okay so pause
for a second after thee after thee
Babylon was a superpower when Daniel was
a captive in it and Daniel is speaking
to the king and he says to the king and
after thee what is he saying after your
one Kingdom hold on wait what did you
just say
imagine you're nebuchadnezzar and you've
just been told and after your kingdom
what do you think nebuchadnezzar is
thinking after my kingdom what are you
talking about after my kingdom we are
it's like saying and after america falls
like how many of you would wait what
we are as a nation what do you mean
after America that's what was being told
to them that's the equivalent of what
was being told to Nebuchadnezzar after
you shall arise another Kingdom inferior
to thee and the third kingdom of brass
which shall bear rule over all the earth
and the fourth Kingdom shall be as
strong as iron for as much as iron
breaks in pieces and subdueth all things
and as iron that breaketh all these
shall it break in pieces and bruise so
what Daniel is telling the King here is
that each one of these are metals gold
followed by silver followed by brass and
then iron each one of these four medals
represented a different kingdom each
kingdom would overthrow the kingdom that
came before it so think about this if if
Babylon was that first Kingdom and
Daniel is alive in the time of Babylon
he has just prophesied he is just
prophesied that Babylon will fall and
that another nation will replace it a
nation described as a chest with arms of
silver so all we need to do now is go
back into our history books and ask the
question hey did the kingdom of Babylon
did the ancient kingdom of Babylon fall
to another nation and the answer is yes
the nation that they fell to was the
medo-persian empire the medo-persian
empire by the way you know what's
interesting Babylon was rich in gold
medo-persia excuse me which came after
Babylon was rich in silver now once it
notices here
Babylon ruled from 612 BC to 539 BC when
they were overthrown by the medo-persian
Empire meet a Persian rule from 539 BC
to 330 BC do you know what Daniel has
just done he's just given prophecy
that as of now is just about 300 years
in length when I say as of now I'm
talking about when the medo-persian
empire finally Falls 300 think about
this now Daniel just gave a prophecy
that spanned almost 300 years Daniel
just gave a prophecy that spanned three
hundred years our weathermen struggle to
prophesy the weather you know the worst
storm ever is about to hit how many
times we heard that this one it's a
category eight and then by the time it
hits landfall oh yeah we're sorry it's
been downgraded to a category one right
you hear you get these all the time oh
yeah this was gonna happen
and Daniel accurately foretold as of the
meter president Empire 300 years of
prophecy but watch this because he also
says that after me the person would fall
after that second King would fall a
third Kingdom would rise in its place
and if you look at history it is it is
our history history shows that it was
the Grecian Empire the Empire of the
Greeks who overthrew overthrew the
medo-persian empire and the Greeks ruled
from 330 BC to 63 BC this is almost 600
years of prophecy that Daniel has
accurately predicted now I want you to
see what's going on here because what
are we doing we're moving down the term
out of history Babylon followed by what
everyone meet Oprah it's on the screen
so you babble on and then metre Persia
and then Greece and then check this out
Greece was rich in bronze
how in the world is Daniel not only
telling the king what he dreamed in the
time that he was alive in the time of
the Babylonian Empire
he's accurately foretelling the nations
that would rise after the Babylonian
Empire he then says that the fourth
kingdom would be strong as iron and
would break and bruised in pieces and
guess what it was the Roman Empire that
overthrew Greece and basically dominated
from 63 BC all the way to 475 AD so just
pause for a moment and I want you to
check this out Daniel who is alive
during the Babylonian Empire has just
foretold almost 1000 years of history in
the future it has just prophesied now
I'm gonna ask you something like let's
say you know some of you in here don't
know me or me you don't know who I am
but I'm saying to you hey guys I want
you to trust me and you're like why
should we trust you and I'll tell you
because I can tell you the future and
you're like yeah you know whatever you
whatever whatever you can't tell me my
fate and I say listen I'm gonna tell you
the future right now I'm gonna tell you
20 things are going to happen between
now and next week in order and if those
20 things come to pass I want you to
explicitly trust me and you guys would
leave here saying yeah that guy was
crazy 20 things going to come to pass
between now and next week let's say that
beginning tonight those 20 things
beginning to come to pass exactly how I
said they were going to come to pass how
many of you by next week would be like
yeah I'm believing anything he says
right and I'm not talking about you know
it the Sun will rise tomorrow
no I'm talking about like you know
things that are very specific things
that could not have been known any other
way this is what Daniel is demonstrating
to us and it's not Daniel that has this
power inside himself he's trying to show
that the God of heaven knows the future
and if he knows the future you can trust
him with your future a thousand year
listen search and get any other holy
book that you'd like to get
and search the record to see if there is
any prophecy any person any God that has
done something like what we have just
seen right here that's 1,000 years no
where else would you find a prophecy
like this
so you're saying pastor but that is far
from where we are right now what about
what in the world is going on today well
listen because Daniel does not stop at a
fourth kingdom does he here's what he
says next he says after the fourth
kingdom remember it was a head of gold
chest lungs of silver what Kingdom
everyone medo-persia deleon thighs of
brass what Kingdom Greece and then legs
of iron what Kingdom Rome and then he
says check he didn't say after Rome
another Kingdom shall
oh boy there we go you didn't see what
you just saw
he doesn't say another kingdom shall
arise after all no he says that Rome
will break down remember
toes of or feet of iron and clay in
other words what he's telling us now is
that the fourth kingdom instead of being
overthrown is going to disintegrate into
smaller kingdoms Wow
like Daniel could have been like man I'm
on a roll and after the fourth Kingdom a
fifth Kingdom shall arrive no he's he
doesn't do that he says after the fourth
Kingdom the fourth Kingdom is gonna
break down into smaller kingdoms let me
ask you a question what happened to the
Roman Empire when it fell after 470
after the four 70s ad was it overthrown
by another by another Kingdom no no no
no Rome fell from the inside it
disintegrated into what we now know as
the European nations so believe it or
not Daniel 2 verse 41 where the sauce
the feet toes part of potters clay and
part of iron the kingdom shall be
divided but there shall be in it the
strength of iron for as much as thou
sawest the iron mixed with miry clay and
as the toes of the feet were part of
iron and part of clay so the kingdom
shall be partly strong and partly broken
what does that mean it's not going to
one cleave it says that in the next
verse whereas thou sawest the iron mixed
with miry clay they shall mingle
themselves with the seed of men but they
shall not cleave one to another even as
iron is not mingled or mixed with clay
so what Daniel is telling us here is
that Rome would break down and you can
see here on a map how roll was divided
after its fall into ten different
kingdoms these kingdoms are what we know
today as Europe Daniel 2 verse 41 says
this we're gonna read it again whereas
thou sawest the feet of an toes part of
potters clay and part of iron the
kingdom shall be divided
but there shall be in it of the strength
of the iron for as much as thou sawest
the iron mixed with miry clay and as the
toes of feet were part of iron and part
of clay so the kingdom shall be partly
strong and partly broken verse 43 and
whereas thou sawest iron mixed with miry
clay they shall mingle themselves with
the seed of men and they shall not want
cleave one to another even as iron is
not mixed with clay so check this out it
might be difficult for you to see that
on the screen but do you realize that to
this day since Rome fell that there have
been people who have come on the scene
that have tried to reunite and re and
form a reunited Roman Empire do you know
that it has never happened what did God
say about these kingdoms they would not
work they would not cleave so check this
out Charlemagne who was a Frankish king
in the 800 800 to 814 attempted to unite
the European kingdoms under one Empire
and he failed the Holy Roman Empire
attempted to do the same thing and they
failed 802 a to 1806 or 800 I'm sorry
1806 Napoleon in 1799 tried to unite and
bring all the nations of Europe together
under one Kingdom and guess what
Napoleon failed Hitler you know what his
goal was to unite Europe under 130 and
guess what it failed to this day let me
pause for a second that is almost 2000
nothing I'm sorry 2600 years let me say
that again in slow motion
hundred years of prophecy that is still
as accurate today as when it was given
you guys I mean what do you say to this
how do you refute how do you say no
wrong didn't overthrow great no this is
history God was giving us news in
advance he was telling us look this is
what's gonna happen and this is how it's
gonna happen Babylon medo-persia Greece
Rome Rome divides into all these
kingdoms these kingdoms will try to
cleave one to another and it will not
happen we are in the toes of this image
right now if you want to know where we
are right now where are we in there's
history according to Daniel chapter 2
were not mad when not in the chest and
arms were not in the belly and thighs
were not the legs we are in the toes and
if you remember something happens after
the toes what happens a stone that is
table without hands smites the image or
hits the image on the feet and the whole
thing shatters meaning all the kingdoms
of this world are destroyed have a
question for you just think about this
think about the odds okay let's say like
you know you were living in time of
babylon and daniel tells you this dream
and you're like come on Daniel Babylon
is not gonna fall and let's say that you
just haven't have like an extra extra
extra long life that lasted like 2,600
years and when when Babylon Falls what
do you like you're like Daniel whoa but
maybe that was luck right because you're
stubborn you're like I don't believe in
God maybe that was luck so then you know
you're going are I mean a pair is that
Daniel lucky guess but then hundreds of
years later Peter pairs or Falls
what are you saying what are you saying
now are you like maybe like whoa is this
God real or well maybe but but you're
kind of closer right you're kind of like
maybe I should be listening and then
another's hundreds hundreds of years
passed and then Greece comes on the
scene and then Greece Falls what are you
saying about this time are you like yeah
Daniel I'm going to trust that what you
say is gonna come are you are you
thinking that right about now
when Rome Falls and you're thinking well
maybe a nation will overthrow Rome but
you see just like Daniel said it
disintegrates into these different
empires are you not like more convinced
than ever that you can trust the vision
that Daniel explains yeah it would be a
no-brainer
so listen to what the Bible says again
Matthew 24 this is Jesus speaking if we
know that what Daniel said has come to
pass down to this very day then we can
know for sure that when Jesus says and
you shall hear of wars and rumors of
wars see that you be not troubled how
many of you believe that we can be not
troubled right if he's saying listen
I've told you the future now I'm telling
you what's going to happen up to the
very end of all things because the Bible
says there will be an end of all things
so now he says listen don't be troubled
these things must come to pass but the
end is not yet can you trust that what
do you think can you trust that yeah if
we could trust if we see the record
God's record all right let's let's look
at this prophecy record and we see whoa
2,000 years 2600 years of his record is
totally accurate then would it be safe
for us to trust what he says is coming
next if he said to us listen I want to
explain to you right now what in the
world is going on would it be safe for
us would it be a sure bet for us to
trust that what God says must be
accurate I believe so
I believe so so he says for nation shall
rise against nation
Kingdom against Kingdom and there shall
be famines and pestilences and
earthquakes and diverse places all these
are the beginning of Sorrows notice what
he says in Matthew 24 verse 10 and then
shall many be offended and shall betray
one another and shall hate one another
huh-huh do you see that yeah he says
this and because iniquity shall abound
the love of many shall wax cold people
will begin to do cold-hearted things can
you see that occurring in our world
today just take a look I'm sure you
probably are familiar with all those
faces on the screen because all of those
people are mass murderers mass murderers
the love of many is waxing cold so I
want you to check this out why is it
happening why is it happening did you
notice something about this image
remember Babylon medo-persia Greece Rome
the head is of what gold how many of you
like gold how many you could use gold
like you know if I had gold lots of gold
would be good thing right alright how
many of you would prefer silver over
gold now because silver is less in value
right alright but uh how many of you
would rather silver than bronze anybody
want pennies like I'd rather a dime than
a penny right I'd even rather a nickel
it like I what you see happening here is
that the metals lose their value the
further down they go are you with me so
if you want to know
pastor what in the world is going on
check this out Daniel 2 is an image of a
man it's not an image of a cow or an
image of a donkey or image of a horse
it's an image of a man while this man
in the vision represents different
kingdoms it's an image of a man in other
words listen guys God is showing us what
happens as man's history continues on
man will become more and more base he
will become more and more debased the
value goes down as the image continues
on and the medals get harder which is
the hardest iron so did I do you look
around the world today and see people
just like hard like no love no it's just
like wow man we live in a in a like kind
of honoring like society where people
are just cold and hard guess what this
vision is telling us why a man can go up
into a building in Las Vegas and without
any feeling take a gun and wipe out 59
people if you want to know why look at
that image this is what happens
the further man moves away from God you
want to know what the world is going on
that vision tells us right there it
tells us why men are becoming filled
with hate it tells us why parents are
can can can kill their children and why
children can kill their parents it tells
us why these things are happening
because the further you go from God the
more debased mankind becomes this is
what we're seeing listen this is very
interesting and we're getting ready to
come to a close here so I want you to
just listen carefully in Genesis chapter
1 verse 26 God said let us make man in
our one and our what so God said let us
make man in our image and in our
likeness God's purpose for man
was to reflect his image yeah but the
Bible tells us in Isaiah chapter 14
verse 12 speaking of this angel named
Lucifer whose name is Satan it says it's
a feynman how are our fallen from heaven
o Lucifer son of the morning how art
thou cut down to the ground which didst
weaken the nation's for thou has said in
thine heart I will ascend into heaven I
will exalt my throne above the stars of
God I will sit also upon the Mount of
the congregation in the size of North
don't worry about all that right now
listen to this last verse I will ascend
above the heights of the clouds I will
be like the Most High who is the Most
High it's gone
Lucifer wanted to be like the Most High
he wanted to take the place of God and
so when Lucifer comes to Adam and Eve in
the garden and he tempts them you'll
remember we'll just skip this verse so
you'll remember after this discussion
and he says Eve you can eat from the
tree and she says no we can't eat
because God said we'll die and then he
says in verse 4 and the serpent said
unto the woman ye shall not surely die
for God does know that in a day there
you eat thereof then your eyes shall be
opened and you shall be as what God's
knowing good and evil what did Lucifer
want to be in heaven he wanted to be
like God what did he tell Adam and Eve
you can be like God you can be your own
God you don't need God ruling over you
telling you what to do and dictating to
you God is a tyrant you can be God for
yourself and if you're a God for
yourself then you don't need to reflect
the image of God you can be made in your
own image in your own one in your own
one so do you remember what was it that
Nebuchadnezzar dreamed what was it it
was a one it was an image of a man
instead of reflecting the character of
God reflects the character of sin
reflects a debased character reflects a
character that as time goes on it gets
worse and worse so the gospel check this
out the purpose of the gospel listen to
this in Colossians 3:10 the purpose of
the gospel is stated here and speaking
about those who have been born again
that they should put on the new man
which is renewed in the knowledge after
the image of him that created him where
there is neither Greek nor Jew
circumcision nor uncircumcision
barbarian nor Scythian bond nor free but
Christ is all in all put on therefore as
the elect of God holy and beloved bowels
of mercy kindness humbleness of mind
meekness long-suffering forbearing one
another and forgiving one another If any
man have a chronic inst you even as
Christ forgave you so also do ye guess
what guys the purpose of the gospel was
to get rid of racial tension gonna see
that there the purpose of the gospel was
so that there will be neither Jew nor
Greek circumcision nor uncircumcision
that all would be one in Christ so this
world is on to that there are two
options one I can stand in the image of
the man in Daniel 2 or the other I can
stand in the image of Christ and if I
stand in the image of Christ guess what
I'm not going to be swallowed up by the
anger and hatred and and and and all
these things that are going on around me
because I'm reflecting Christ's image
but if I stand in the image of the man
in Daniel chapter 2 guess what I'm going
to reflect that character and before I
know it I'll become as debased as those
I'm looking at saying man they are crazy
the purpose of the gospel is to restore
man into the image of God into the image
of Christ
the song the very last thing to happen
in this image as and in the days of
these Kings shall the God of heaven set
up a kingdom which shall never be
destroyed and the Kingdom shall not be
left to other people but it shall break
in pieces and consume all these kingdoms
and it shall stand forever for as much
as the sauce that the stone was cut out
with out of the mountain without hands
that in breaking pieces the iron the
brass the clay the silver and the gold
the great God has made known to the king
what shall come to pass Hereafter and
the dream is certain and the
interpretation thereof is sure God is
telling us listen you don't have to
guess about this now if I told you that
a man was coming out of the sky to get
us one day and you knew nothing about
the Bible you would think you're crazy
men don't come from out the sky yes who
is this Jesus you're talking about it's
going to come and destroy this earth but
guess what God says okay I'm gonna give
you a prophecy and and and at the end of
this prophecy you see or you see Babylon
medo-persia Greece Rome
you see Rome dividing you see anger
hatred you see all these things
happening if those had a hundred percent
chance of coming to pass and they came
to pass what are the odds that the stone
which represents the coming of Jesus
Christ what are the odds that that will
happen are you are you it's a certainty
you don't have to guess you don't have
to wonder you have to be like well maybe
it's a no no we have history real live
secular history to back up what the
Bible has said and that being the case
we can know ok I see God is trying to
prepare us for a major event it's not a
bomb that's going to destroy this world
that stone is not a nuclear bomb that
stone represents Jesus Christ and how
amazing for God to put this in the Bible
for us so that whether you're a believer
or number whatever you are
he's trying to let you know hey guys I'm
coming I don't want to catch you off
guard so please understand that I have
your future in my hands understand that
I'm the God that can tell you your
future so I want you to trust me with
your future what a god what a God that
would be willing to do that listen
there's a final sign and we'll wrap it
up with this final sign because you got
to see this final sign Matthew 24 10 and
then shall be and then many shall be
offended and shall betray one another
and shall hate one another and many
false prophets shall arise and shall
deceive many and because iniquity shall
abound the love of many shall wax cold
but he that shall endure unto the end
the same shall be saved and then here's
a final sign and this gospel of the
kingdom shall be preached in all the
world for a witness unto all nations and
then shall the end what does the final
sign according to the Bible the gospel
will be preached in all the world
the book of Revelation picks up on this
very same theme because there are three
angels described in this book and I
listen we don't have time to this I just
need you to see it because there's so
much there we don't have time to go
there but it will happen if you're
interested listen revelation 14:6 John
says I saw another angel fly in the
midst of heaven having the everlasting
gospel to preach unto them that dwell on
the earth to every nation kindred tongue
and people saying with a loud voice fear
God and give glory to him that word fear
means reverence it doesn't mean be
afraid of reverence God and give glory
to him for the hour of his judgment has
come and worship Him that made heaven
the earth the sea and the fountains of
water that first angel's message is the
everlasting gospel to preach to every
nation kindred tongue and people that
message is to go into all it's a very
special message that is actually not
being heard in too many places number
two another angel follows and says
therefore another angel saying Babylon
is fallen is fallen that great city
because
made all nations drink of the wine of
the wrath of her fornication this is the
downfall of a system that is designed to
deceive planet Earth that's what the
Bible is talking about here and we don't
have time to go into this but listen the
third angel followed saying with a loud
voice if any man worship the Beast and
His image and receive his mark in his
forehead or in his hand
ever heard of the mark of the beast this
is where it comes from the same shall
drink of the wine of the wrath of God
which is poured out without mixture into
the cup of his indignation I want you to
notice this If any man worship the Beast
and his want and His image and his image
beloved there's the image of God and
there's the image of the Beast the
question is which image will you reflect
and right after those three angels the
Bible says I looked and behold a white
cloud and upon the cloud one sat like
unto the Son of man having a head having
on his head a golden crown and in his
hand a sharp sickle this is the rock
coming to cleanse the earth coming to
redeem his people listen Jesus said
these words let not your heart be
troubled what wait a minute Lord we're
going through there's a whole bunch of
craziness going on and he says what let
not your heart be troubled you believe
in God believe also in me in my father's
house are many mansions if it were not
so I would have told you I go to prepare
a place for you and if I go and prepare
a place for you I will come again
that's not our guess that's not a it's
certain I will come again and receive
you unto myself that where I am there
you may be also
but I'm it tonight has just been an
overview of what in the world is going
on tonight I have only tried to show you
to demonstrate to you that out of all
the sources of news that you can trust
the Bible is
best source because it will not tell you
wrong and when you have the Bible as
your source you can rest assured that
God will reveal what is coming and how
you can be prepared for it so I want to
close with this very simple appeal as
have this closing song I want you to
listen you eat one of you got a
registration form and my appeal is very
simple some of you may be visiting here
only for tonight only for the first time
but tonight you're saying you know what
I'm interested I want to know a little
bit more about this what is the mark of
the beast what what is this image of the
Beast and what is this thing to happen
at the end of time call that these three
angels messages I want to learn more
because I want to be ready and I want to
be prepared I want to invite you to take
that form fill it out if you just want
to put your email I will contact you
personally so fill it out and then our
our deacons will will collect it as you
are leaving before you leave here
tonight and remember remember that Jesus
Jesus is coming it's not a matter of if
it's a matter of when if you haven't
given your heart to the Lord I really
want to encourage you there's not a lot
of time to wait that's what I believe
and so I just want to encourage you
tonight if you have not given your life
to the Lord I want to encourage you to
do that now you can even write that on
the sheet hey I want to dedicate my life
to the Lord doesn't mean you're joining
this church you're just saying tonight I
want to dedicate my life to the Lord and
and I want to begin to understand the
Word of God better so please as they
sing the song
take time to fill out that that sheet if
the if God moves you and they were
collected at the end of the song in
times like these you need a Savior
like these you need a name core be very
sure be very sure your anchor rules
[Music]
encrypts the solid
this book is Jesus
yes he's the world
this rock is Jesus
[Music]
be very sure be very sure
your anchor holds and grips the solid in
times like these you need the Bible in
times like these
jeez Oh peanut I told be very sure be
very sure your anchor holds and grips
the solid rock this rock is Jesus yes
he's the one
this rock is Jesus
[Music]
be very sure be very sure your anchor
holds and grips the solid in times like
these I have a save you're in times like
these I have a name code I'm very sure
I'm very sure my anchor
holds and grips the solid rock this rock
is Jesus yes he's a war
this rock is Jesus the only one I'm very
sure I am very sure my inger rules in
grapes are slowly
[Music]
how many of you feel that you can answer
that question a little bit better after
this presentation what in the world is
going on Amen it is our prayer that
you'll share it with your friends and
family and take the message to heart
most of you received a registration form
when you came if you would be so kind to
turn that into the ushers at the door
and if you did not receive one please
ask the usher for registration form fill
it out and give it back to them as well
and finally like for you to all take a
very deep breath can you smell food food
is cooking or has been cooked it is a
fundraiser tonight for our pathfinders
those for those of you who are not
familiar with what a pathfinder is it's
similar to the Girl Scouts and Boy
Scouts of America and they're raising
money tonight so it's all for the young
people to continue to do positive things
but they also learn about the Word of
God and so if you would like to stay you
are welcome you're all invited to stay
and again it it is a fundraiser for the
Pathfinder Club so at this time you're
all dismissed want to thank you for
coming out on this Saturday evening and
god bless you
[Music]
wanted